Go.
[music]
Hey. Hey. Heat. Heat. [music]
>> [music]
>> Hey,
[music]
[music] hey,
hey.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Doney [music]
back.
Heat. Heat. N.
[music]
>> [music]
>> D.
[music]
Bang dang dang dang dang dang dang dang
dang dang it.
>> [music]
>> going.
[music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
[music]
[music] Heat. Heat.
Heat. [music]
[music]
Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hey.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat. Hey, Heat.
[music]
Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Good morning. You're watching the
program with Ted Roll and John Kuryaku.
It's Tuesday, November 18th, 2025. And
if you're watching this on the internet,
you're probably lucky because much of
the internet is down today uh due to a
problem uh with the internet
infrastructure company Cloudflare. Uh
banks are down, X is down, Truth Social
is down, Chat GPT is down, Open AI
overall is down, um Grock is down. Uh
you know, it's at a certain point it'll
be just like the Blizzard of 77 where
it'll be shorter to announce the list of
things that are still open. Good
morning, John.
>> Good morning, Ted. How are you?
>> I'm I'm I'm better than uh Cloudflare.
[laughter]
I'm up and running, such as it is. Um
lots to talk about. Uh we're going to be
talking about uh the [clears throat]
James Comey indictment. Uh I'm sure
you'll have one or two things to say
about that, John.
>> Um also the effect of Trump policies on
uh student enrollment at American
colleges and universities. We have some
numbers. Um they're down uh basically
17% this year. That's you know that
seemed actually a little lower than I
expected uh that drop to be. Um South
Africa that's the main story today for
us. Uh Israel is uh basically seems to
be quietly ethnically cleansing by drip
drip drip uh Palestinians out of Gaza uh
to
>> other countries. Yeah. Like 150 people
at a time. and and also extracting money
from them uh at the same time to do so.
>> And the UN Security Council appropo
visav that um is just uh signed off on
Trump's plan. John, you you called this
yesterday. You said this is exactly what
was going to happen and I'm just
surprised by just exactly how you were
totally spot on. I was like really
[laughter] that happened
but uh and we have some problem awful
awful meetings. Awful. And the the sad
truth is Russia and China just don't
care about the Middle East. And if if
voting yes will make the Americans shut
up, then they'll squeeze out of the US
side whatever they can and then just
vote yes.
>> It's really it's really strange because
it's so like the thing is, you know, I'm
a I'm a former banker and one of the
things I learned from negotiating
contracts was it's not about
necessarily, you know, a good deal. It's
about you need a contract that works and
I don't see how the current 20point plan
by Trump I don't see how it functions in
a number of ways including for Israel. I
I just don't see how it really works. Um
and we can we can talk about that and we
we will um John we have a couple of
comments before we get to the main
topics. comment for me. Eric Adams in
kissing that wall in Jerusalem uh in a
photo saying that he came to Israel to
let them know he serves them as mayor of
New York City. I mean, you know, Eric
Adams is yesterday's news. He's not
going to be the mayor.
>> Yeah, he's a nobody.
>> He's a nobody. He's a he's he's a he's
on notice. He's been fired and uh he's
But still, I mean, it is it is it's a
it's not a good look. and John uh
Langghorn Langghorn Clemens is saying
just heard a retelling of your fib setup
story with the Japanese ambassador. Not
calling it into question, just curious
how common is it for Japan to send
people to the United States that can't
speak English. I I I have thoughts about
that after you answer that. Go ahead.
>> That that's a very good question. I and
I I don't take umbrage with it at all.
It's a very good question. The Japanese
are unique in this respect in that for
example um when I was in Bahrain the
Japanese council general in Chicago was
named Japanese ambassador to Bahrain and
we were kind of excited like okay the
guy spent three years in Chicago now
he's going to come here he couldn't even
say hello my name is in English it's
ridiculous the Japanese are very unusual
in that respect in that a lot of them
just don't even speak a a single word. I
don't know how in the world they they
get through this.
>> The thing is it's their [clears throat]
national character. They're arrogant.
They don't know. John,
>> exactly.
>> I worked I you know, as you know, I
worked for the Industrial Bank of Japan
Trust Company in the late 80s and um
most of my colleagues were sent to the
United States and all claimed that they
spoke fluent English.
Like the people you described, they
couldn't speak English for [__] They
could not and and and it was like they
were and like if an American didn't
understand like like a waiter what they
what they wanted,
>> they would be like that person is stupid
and I'd be like you can't speak English.
>> And they use the word a lot. In fact,
>> I I wasn't going to tell the story, but
I will now that you say that. Um the
Japanese ambassador, the new Japanese
ambassador in Bahrainia just arrived
from Chicago. This was 19
94 or 1995. And so we get this
invitation
that
um the ambassador is inviting our
ambassador, our deputy chief of mission,
our political officer, our economic
officer, and our commercial officer. So
it was five of us to dinner at his
residence. And one thing about the
Japanese, when they have a dinner, they
they it's no holds barred. It's caviar
and the most expensive steaks and it's
incredible.
>> They're like, "Hey, we're going to have
dinner at the at the Japanese
ambassador's residence. This is going to
be great." So, we go there and um
>> we're all just kind of standing around
and the younger guys spoke some English.
The ambassador didn't speak a word.
Well, barely a word, as you'll see in a
moment. And so um we finally sit down uh
after you know an hour of chitchat
pleasantries we sit down at the dining
room table and our ambassador says so
Mr. Ambassador to what do we owe this
pleasure and the Japanese ambassador
says your president
he's stupid.
It turned out that when he was in
Chicago, he somehow struck up this
acquaintance with Dan Quail, who had
been the vice president. And Dan Quayle
said, "Oh, Bill, Bill Clinton cheats on
his wife. He's no good." So, the
Japanese ambassador called us all
together to tell us. He didn't really
literally mean he's stupid. It's that
his English was so bad that he just
couldn't convey himself. And our
ambassador, David Ransom, loveliest guy
I've ever worked for, he stood up and he
says, "Well, [clears throat] thank you
for your hospitality." And he says to
us, "Gentlemen," and we all got up and
walked right out
>> because yeah, you're not going to stand
for the head of state being insulted
that way.
>> Absolutely not appropriate. And we
walked out. But the point of the of the
story was um it's not unusual for
Japanese to not speak any English at
all. even though they're posted in the
United States. And that's
>> and that was true about international
banking at the highest levels. I mean,
IBJ was essentially the Federal Reserve
Bank of Japan. Wow. And and and the New
York branch was the most prestigious
branch to work at. Um and it's because
in the 80s, right, that connection
between New York business and Tokyo, and
it was the same thing. I mean, I was
amazed. I mean, don't get don't get me
wrong. I mean there was a lot to like
about the Japanese but there was a lot
to dislike as well. Um [laughter]
uh you know during that period and I'll
tell this one story and we'll we'll move
on. Um you'll remember that that every
there was a whole spate of biggest art
sales of all time during that period and
uh Van Go Sunflowers was one of them. Um
Sumitomo Bank bought the I or was it
Mitsubishi? is either Sumitomo or Summit
Mitsubishi Bank bought Sunflowers for
something like $60 million. I know
there's several versions of it. I think
this is like Sunflowers number four.
Anyway, it's the one or it's one of the
ones. Anyway, it was the biggest art
sale of all time. And my boss was like
an art lover. He's like, I want to see
that. I want to see it. So he made a
pretextual excuse to have a business
meeting with the president of the bank
because he heard the painting was in the
bank's office in the bank president's
office that they had put it there. So we
go over there and he was just like he
was always like scheming like this. So
we had no business really with them. It
was just like just we just wanted to be
in there for 15 minutes just to see the
painting. So we go over there and you
know sure enough there it is and it was
hanging over the radiator
>> over the over right like like directly
above like with where the heat's coming
out directly underneath and I we didn't
even my boss and my boss was brilliant
like you I loved working for this guy.
He was my best boss ever and Shabuya
looks at me I look at him you know we
don't even have to say a word to each
other just like holy [__] We walk out
of there and he I remember he just says
disgusting. He's like we don't you know
like the he's like the Japanese will get
their comeuppants we're [__] Um you
know because it was like they were
flying high in the 80s and buying real
estate all over the place.
>> We thought the US was done
>> the Japanese. Yeah,
>> we did. Yeah. Remember there were those
movies like uh about like American, you
know, workers having to learn how to do
jumping jacks in the morning at the
factories and stuff like that.
I'm glad that didn't. [laughter]
>> Honestly, they would not have been good
overlords. Um, so let's see. Uh, we
should so yeah, what do you want to talk
about first because we're getting a late
start here.
>> Well, you know, we should we should say
real quickly that uh Saudi Crown Prince
Muhammad bin Salman is in uh Washington
today. So, this sort of completes his
rehabilitation after ordering the uh the
murder and dismemberment of a Washington
Post journalist. Uh, you know, Trump
loves the Saudis. The Saudis love Trump.
You can bet your bottom dollar that the
Trump family is going to be wealthier uh
at the end of the day today than it was
in the morning. And the Saudis are going
to go back with a a giant package of
F-35s, which is the reason why he's here
in the first place. We the position of
the United States is that we would not
sell F-35s to the to the Saudis because
>> the Chinese have infiltrated the Saudi
defense industry and we're afraid that
the that the Chinese would steal the the
design and the plans uh for the F-35.
And Trump announced yesterday on the eve
of NBS's visit that he would sell F-35s
to the Saudis. So there you go. and he
will
that will happen. So, so I mean how does
that affect things? Uh, currently Israel
is the only Middle Eastern country that
has F-35s.
>> We've also promised them to the United
Arab Emirates,
>> uh, which is another reason why the
Saudis were angry and wanted them
because traditionally the Saudis are
first and the Emirates are a very close
second. We've flipped it on this F-35.
So, yeah, the Israelis have them, the
Emirates are getting them, and now the
Saudis are getting them. So that makes
everybody happy.
>> Everyone has to have the right toys.
What do you make of the reporting in
that we're hearing about this visit
where people say it's the assessment
they keep saying this it is the
assessment of the intelligence community
that uh you know MBS ordered the Kosogi
killing. Um that's true. It's also the
assessment of just common sense and
facts. I mean, the Turk the Turks were
they recorded they have an audio
recording that's on the internet that
anybody can hear of MBS being basically
tortured and killed. Um, yeah. In fact,
they know exactly what happened to him.
>> The Saudis started chopping him up while
he was still alive
>> and he's screaming as they're cutting
off his arms.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, and and and then they
dissolved him in acid and and dumped him
into the uh Istanbul
uh sewer system.
>> I mean I mean it's not and it's also
just like oh the order that he ordered
the killing. That's
>> okay true, but it's like in this case
the details really matter. I mean he was
lured to a consulate and while his
fiance was waiting outside and they did
that to him. I mean it's a I mean I know
the US kills people every day. I mean
you know talk to the Venezuelans but
this is on a whole level of of perity
and like I mean basically to me the
reason it's less about Kosigible but if
I were the American president it's kind
of like the Saudis saying you know we
can do whatever the [__] we want and
you're our [__] because we have so much
oil and money you're going to do
whatever the [__] we want and like it. I
mean, that to me is the that's that's
the real, you know, power politics
problem for with this whole thing.
>> That's right. That
>> we need to Let's um put Robbie in.
Robbie has some housekeeping to take
care of. This is day two of Robbiey's
return. And we're going to welcome back
Robbie again. Good. So, good to have
you, especially on a day like this with
so many tech issues. You had some
housekeeping to do and uh so go ahead
and do your housekeeping. And also,
you're going to have to the ads you're
going to have to feed me. remember
because I'm not on the Rumble room.
Okay.
>> No, no, I got that. So, uh, good news is
the audio works. The bad news is if
you're on YouTube, I cannot see your
chat. It's gone. So, you're talking to
yourselves.
>> Oh, now if you can see it,
>> it's just not coming across
crossplatform. So, I'm not able to see
it on the studio end.
>> So, if y'all want me to put your
comments up on the screen and be able to
just kind of feed them over to John and
Ted, jump over here to Rumble because I
can see those naturally because I'm a
Rumble Studios. That helps. I'll also
I'm gonna pull up that chat, too.
>> Yeah. Also, if you come over to Rumble,
frankly, John and Ted get paid more and
more money is always a good thing.
Rumble pays much better than YouTube.
And lastly, uh if you want to get a copy
of What's Left, Ted's book, we're going
to be pimping that out. Just go to
raw.com. You can order yourself a copy,
a signed copy of What's Left. Uh Ted
actually sent that to me and gave me a
copy and then and then my son bought a
copy when he was here in Callispel. And
speaking of buying, I'm going be working
on setting up book signings for Ted. So
if you have a bookstore in your town,
unlike mine, please email me. West
Glacier Gaming. Let me know and I will
see if I can get a book signing set up
in your town with Ted
>> Westlac Gaming atgmail.
>> Correct. West Glaciergam@gmail.com.
I'm going to work on building a producer
email. sounds a little bit more
professional and less [__] but I am
[__] so I'm going away now.
>> Okay. And I take you away. All right.
Uh, housekeeping kept. All right. So,
what what next? Shall we talk about
Comey? Maybe get that out of the way.
>> Yeah, let's talk about Comey. Sure.
>> All right. So, so basically the the um
federal magistrate judge um complained
that Lindsay prosecutor Lindseay Hallan
[__] up the James Comey indictment. Uh
she issued a really angry 24page uh
reaming where she basically said accused
the prosecutor of fundamental and highly
prejuditial misstatements of law. Um the
judge William Fitzpatrick uh ordered
that uh all grand jury materials be
released to Comey's attorneys um saying
that basic this is I guess common
misconduct right like is that the
defense doesn't receive everything that
the prosecutor has although they're
supposed to always do that but you and I
hear those stories all the time.
>> Um how serious is this? Is this a
political judge or is or is is he right?
>> Um no this is serious. I think the judge
is right. This is one of those This is
one of those situations where um
where the government picked the person
that they wanted to screw and then
looked through the law books for
something to charge him with. Remember
we talked about um we talked about the
book uh three felonies a day by Dr.
Harvey Silverglate. He's a professor of
law at Harvard who says that that we are
so overcriminalized and so overregulated
in this country that the average person
on the average day going about his or
her normal business commits three
felonies. And that's this situation.
They hate Comey. They want to screw
Comey. So they just look for some
felonies to charge him with. And
I hope this is not the case with John
Brennan because I know John Brennan to
be a criminal.
>> [snorts]
>> Um, with Comey, it's much less clear and
it looks like this case is falling apart
very very quickly. Remember, they they
wanted to charge Comey in the uh Eastern
District of Virginia and the
uh US attorney for the Eastern District
said, "I'm not seeing any crimes." And
so what they did was they just fired the
US attorney and named a new US attorney
who said, "Oh, I'll find some crimes."
and the judge is just saying, "Oh, no,
you don't.
>> That's not how that that's not how this
is supposed to work." Uh, I want to
thank Kokakei over in uh uh in Rumble
for becoming a paid monthly sub
supporter of the DProgram show.
>> Wonderful. Thank you, Kaki.
>> Totally. Um, so yeah, by the way, this
Cloudflare thing, um, Cloudflare is sort
of glossing over this. Uh at first they
claimed that it was a a poorly
administered update which happened a few
years ago. I'm sure you'll recall. Um
but you know then I'm thinking that uh
they said they reported an unusual spike
of traffic right before the crash. That
sounds to me like a denial of service
attack. Yes.
>> Um
>> yeah,
>> I'm looking at chat GPT right now and I
just get an error screen and it says
please unblockchallenges.cloudfair.com
to proceed. So then I went on to comet
to try perplexity and it gives me
exactly the same message.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And apparently Canva has the
same exact thing. So I mean CloudFlare's
all over the place. And of course it's
just a reminder that uh the internet is
basically tied together with like duct
tape and bailing wire. Remember when
when this was sold to us, you know how
like compact discs were sold as like
they're indestructible. They can't
scratch and they will never skip. They
will last thousands of years. And the
internet was sold to us like even in
nuclear war it can't be destroyed. It
will all have a workaround. I'm like I
don't think we I I think like a a good
big thunderstorm will probably take it
the whole thing down.
>> Oh my god. Yeah. I I'm afraid the same
is is uh is true. And I wonder, you
know, is this gonna have any There you
go. That's right.
There you go. Good. I'm looking at your
uh your feed or the feed on Rumble right
now. You just put up the book. So good.
Anyway, I'm I'm hoping that this doesn't
affect banking or something today or
even if it does affect banking, they can
get this dog on thing fixed in the next
few minutes because, you know, we need
to
>> the market's the mark the market's open
in in eight minutes in the in New York.
>> You're exactly right. And weren't we
just talking yesterday about uh the film
Trading Places and how um on the
commodities exchange they no longer use
these little slips of paper. Everything
is computerized. Everything is
computerized. Talking about the global
economy here.
>> So they they best get their act
together.
>> Too much [__] is automated. I mean it's
like you know I don't know. It's like
everyone should learn from the Iranians
with the uh the stuckset virus. It's
like,
>> yeah, remember that
>> Iranian nuclear scientists shouldn't
shouldn't need to cyber commute. You
guys should drive to the plant and and
work there. Um, here we go. Um, if you
haven't we just got an ad to do this
here. Uh, if you haven't already, make
sure you download the Rumble app. It's
free, simple to use, and the best way to
stay connected to the content you want.
Once you've got it, search for my for
our channel and hit follow. That way,
you'll get a notification every time we
go live. No missed shows, no extra
steps. You can grab it right now using
the link in the description of the or
the pinned live chat. Download it to
your phone and you're ready to go. And
if you prefer watching on the big screen
as I do, Rumble is available on all
major streaming devices and smart TVs.
Just search for Rumble, follow the
channel, and be part of the action.
>> All right, you're right.
>> At least we solved some problems. We
solved my my uh packet loss problem
yesterday. Um um that was very
irritating. So good to have Robbie back.
Did I say that? It's really good to have
Robbie back. Um, so James Comey, does he
So if Comey, the Comey case falls apart,
will Trump will Trump come back for
another uh for the will the DOJ come
back for another whack at the pinata or
will they politically say, you know
what, we looked foolish and best to move
on.
>> You know, isn't it sad that we even have
to stop and consider these two
positions? Um,
>> yeah,
>> my guess is they're going to jump up and
down and and scream and holler and then
move on. I think they have a stronger
case against Brennan because the
argument with Brennan
the argument with Brennan is
>> Comey's more popular politically than
Brennan.
>> Much much more popular. Good point. The
the thing with Brennan is that
the accusation is that he tried to
initiate a coup. uh tried to deny the
voters in 2016 their choice of president
of the United States. And um
>> that's pretty serious.
>> It is. And and the argu it's it's uh
sedicious. What do they call it? Or or
something something sedition. uh I
forget the term that they've been using,
but anyway, uh
they argue that the conspiracy
remained ongoing
until
uh Brennan was charged.
>> And so there's no statute of
limitations, at least not one that can
prevent his his trial.
Somebody, one of my attorneys sent me
the the videos a couple of weeks ago of
Brennan being confronted at George Mason
University and and poking that
congressional candidate in the chest.
Remember? And then
>> like three or four hours later, he's
arguing with some heckler on the on the
subway platform at the Virginia Square
Metro Station. And my lawyer wrote,
"What do you make of this?" And I I
watched both of the videos a number of
times. And I wrote back and I said,
"He's scared." That's what this is. I've
known John Brennan for 35 years and I've
never seen him lose his cool.
>> Really?
>> That's because he's scared.
>> Well, wow. And and he's and he's
responding with anger as many people do.
Fo, thanks for the buck.
>> Black Friday dream purchase this year.
John,
>> what's your one? What would be your your
dream purchase for Black Friday? You
know, the day after Thanksgiving.
>> For Black Friday, [laughter]
>> it's usually it's electronics typically.
>> Yeah. When when I was a kid, I never
understood it when I would ask my
parents what they wanted for Christmas
and and they would say nothing. We have
everything we want. My mom would always
say, "All I want is to have good kids,
right?"
>> But I'm at that point now. I'm 61.
You're 62.
I I have everything that I want and need
and I just I just don't need anything.
>> No, I know. I'm I'm the same way. The
truth is if I need something, I I I just
get it, you know? I mean
>> Yeah. Just get it.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's not like Yeah. It's
It's not like being a kid where you just
don't have that cash flow. I mean,
>> h you know, I I probably do need a new
scanner, John. I have a flat I'm a
cartoonist and I have a I need a big
flatbed scanner like an 11 by7.
>> There you go.
>> And uh my my current one, however, it's
the oldest working electronic in my
house. It's from 1997
and it's still going strong. So, you
know,
>> that's amazing.
>> Hullet Packard. Uh yeah, I had it's it's
and I mean it's like a beast. I kind of
like want to see how long it'll go. Um,
anyway, so all right, let's we can talk
a little bit about we'll get to the
meaty stuff a little bit later. Get the
get the easy ones out of the way, knock
them down. Um, so, uh, obviously we all
know what's going on with Trump's, uh,
you know, anti-immigration policies, and
he's been doing everything he can to
lean on colleges and universities to,
uh, deny student visas so that they
can't attend. Anyway, long story short,
international student enrollments are
dropping. If they, if it hadn't been
dropping, you'd have to wonder what the
hell is going on. But the Institute of
International Education surveys 828
American institutions um and they they
find a 17% drop in firsttime enrollments
this year. Only a 1% decline overall. So
overall enrollment, but they say it's
going to, you know, obviously it'll
snowball. Um you know, John, I'm torn
about this. How do you feel about it?
Yeah, I I'm I'm a little torn, too. Um
I don't know, man. You know, it just
seems to me like we have we have so many
important things happening. It's almost
not possible to be worried about
everything.
>> There aren't enough day to worry about
>> You have to do anxiety triage.
>> Yeah, that you know what? That's a great
way to say it. Yeah, it is. It's anxiety
triage.
>> Yes. And so, yeah. No, it's like, well,
I mean,
>> well, let me
>> I went to college and I I valued my
relationship with international with
foreign students a lot.
>> Oh my god, me too. When I when I first
went to college, um most of the upper
classmen who were foreign nationals were
Iranians because they had been stuck in
the United States because of the Iranian
revolution.
>> By the time I left, most of them were
Lebanese because they had fled the
Lebanese civil war. But looking at this
operationally, Ted, we want foreign
students to come here and we want them
to study hard sciences. Why?
>> So the CIA can recruit them now as
students and send them back to work in
the Chinese uh missile program or the
Russian nuclear program or the Iranian
nuclear program or whatever. And there
are already assets in place. So, we want
foreign students here, especially
foreign PhD students here.
>> Does anyone with Trump's ear tell him
that from the from the CIA?
>> I doubt it. I doubt it.
>> I doubt it because remember, most of the
time the CIA director most of the time
is a is a political appointee and
they're really not thinking about these
longer term issues.
>> It's I mean it does it does bug me that
like what a profit center they are. Um,
and that like I think it was Harvard
that said that 27% of all of their
undergraduate enrollment was
international students. And think about
how incredibly
comp competitive is it is to attend
Harvard. I mean literally
one out of four spots there is is taken
by foreigners. I mean I can't think that
one out of four spots at the SBAN or the
University of Tokyo are are taken by
foreign students.
>> Right. Yes. I doubt it, but I think
you're right.
>> Oxford, I don't think so. Um, well, yes.
Okay, good point. Anything else to say
about that [laughter] before we move on?
>> No, just that it it could be a very
important uh operational opportunity
lost.
>> This is a funny comment. I'm So, I'm
just going to read it. Toli says, "I
want my adult stepson to move out so I
can experience time with my husband
before I die. Can I get that somewhere
on on on Black Friday? He's only 36, but
I don't feel badly one little bit. Only
36. Don't worry. Once once they hit 42,
they fly the nest. It'll be fine.
That's really funny though. But that's
the new economy. I mean, that's how
things are now, right? Um
>> Yeah, that's
>> Oh, this is a good question. This is
from uh Rod and Goo 9864. Thanks for the
two euros. Um can Trump and Mandani find
a way to coexist? I'm glad you brought
up that question because there is uh
there's reporting today that says that
um Mdani uh asked his team asked Trump's
team for a meeting and uh Trump said
that he's amendable to sitting down with
Mdani and talking John what do you make
of the fact that like all the people who
came out so harshly against Mumani the
communist who was going to uh you know
restore to bring bring Marxist Leninism
to the five burrows
Um, now you know you have your favorite
uh Christidi Greek groceryer. Um, he
says he's not only not leaving the city,
he wants people to cooperate with Mumani
so that things work out really well.
Trump, who had all sorts of shitty
things to say about Mandani, is now
saying, "Oh, I'll meet with him." Um,
Governor Hokll, who refused to endorse
him until the last second. I guess I'm
still waiting. Hillary Clinton might
endorse Mandani like halfway through his
term. Um, but I mean every all these
establishment I mean Mdani is wielding a
lot of power. So it's a two-part
question.
>> Um, how do they look in all this? And
then here's the other thing. How do how
can voters take any of this seriously
when you, you know, when they hear this
person is evil and terrifying and
far-left and communist. Oh, hey, welcome
to the White House. How's it going?
>> Yeah. Right, Ted. You and I are both old
enough to remember
>> when the Democratic Party was a big tent
party.
>> When when everybody from Ted Kennedy to
George Wallace were Democrats, you know,
when when almost every Senate seat in
every southern southern state was held
by a conservative Democrat, and I mean
conservative
Democrat.
>> Yep. And the Democrats claim that
they're still a Big 10 party and they're
not. They're not. Now they're so middle
of the road that they're just stuck.
It's like being stuck in neutral where
they don't want these conservatives, but
they also don't want these liberals
either. And it's going to it's going to
end up being the demise of the
Democratic party.
>> Well, I mean, the question if the
Republican party doesn't fall apart
first. I mean, the civil war between the
uh Trump wing and the MTG wing is really
heating up.
>> Um, right now, I got to say, I didn't I
didn't expect to see this. I mean, Trump
is still such a cany politician. like
even the way that he that he's pivoting
on the on the Epstein files, it's it's
really I mean it's you know it's a
masterclass really in uh in many ways
but even though it's cynical, but I
didn't but I don't know that he's
winning the war with MTG right now.
She's the one who's coming out smelling
like roses.
>> They they both backed off yesterday, but
she she has won this this little
kuruffle. Yes.
I mean, her her reputation has improved
dramatically. I think that the real the
the the secret sauce was admitting that
she had contributed to the toxic
atmosphere and expressing regret for it.
I mean, I don't know about you, John, I
mean, I'm a I'm a huge I, you know, I
grew up Catholic. I'm a huge sucker for
penance and and and repentance. If
someone if someone's an [__] and they
say, "Oh, God, I was an [__] and I
shouldn't have been and I'm sorry." I'm
like, "I got nothing. you win. You know,
that's because that's all you can ask
from people. They can't go back in time.
>> I agree. I agree.
Robbie uh Robbie is saying that Tucker
has doubled down. Tucker has doubled
down, you know, and it's funny. People
ask me all the time what I make of of
the new Tucker Carlson. And
>> all I can say is, you know, the guy
answers to nobody. And when you have
when you don't work for anybody but
yourself and you don't you're not doing
it for the money, you can say anything
that you know your heart desires. And
and we're seeing a totally liberated and
free Tucker Carlson right now.
>> I can't even imagine. Speaking of which,
like when you when he was at Fox, like
how many memos came down like, "Okay, so
our our our point on this topic or this
person is this. Don't deviate from that.
I mean, I know from uh internally I've
heard about how MSNBC, like now uh NBC
now, how they they did that all the
time. I mean, they they sent the word
down like, you know, Ed Schultz, right?
Uh you know, he he was told in no
uncertain terms, you can't discuss
Bernie Sanders during the during the
Democratic primary. Like really, you
can't talk about a major primary
candidate? Ed was a friend of mine uh
and we ended up working um at RT
together. He um he never forgave MSNBC
for doing that.
>> Never forgave them.
>> Well, it's disgusting. And of course,
you know, I mean I I think I told you
the story, but like my agent uh you know
had told me that they MSNBC was
interested in trying me out like you
know late night on a weekend
>> and they said the only thing I had to
promise was to never criticize the
Democratic Party.
And yeah, and and I I remember what I
said. I said, "Well, you know, tell them
like when it's like France and there's
26 parties and if there's one out of the
26 that I can't criticize, that's fine.
But there's only two, so how can you do
your job?" It wasn't even a matter of
integrity. It was literally like from a
practical standpoint, I don't know how
you can do this without sounding
ridiculous. And the truth is, you can't.
They do sound ridiculous.
>> Um, I want to say two things. First of
all, Marorrow, thank you very much for
the donation. $4.99.
Appreciate that very much. And then
James Jamalis, hey James. Uh James says,
um John would love Lincoln stove uh
stovepipe hat for Christmas. You know,
the stove the stove pipe hat is on
display in the Smithsonian's Museum of
American History. It's an incredible
thing to see. But I will add that
>> the only He must have had several.
Yeah, but the one that he was wearing
the night that he was killed
>> was on display. Yeah.
>> He [snorts] actually had taken it off
and had put it on a table next to him,
so there's not like a hole in it or
anything.
>> Right. Because a gentleman didn't wear a
hat inside.
>> That's right. That's right.
>> That still bugs me. I'm old enough to
like when I see dudes wearing baseball
caps inside, I'm like, that [__]
thing off, [__] So, um, this past
week I spent in Oxford, Ohio with my
with my son Max, my third son. And, um,
Max loves antique malls as much as I do.
So, we drove to Indianapolis, which
isn't too terribly far away. It's about
two hours from where he goes to school.
>> Hour drive.
>> Boring, boring, boring. Just farm after
farm after farm. It's enough to make you
want to cut your throat. Anyway, um
there's this one
dealer that we like that I've bought
stuff from before because he he has
impeccable provenence for everything
that he sells. And I bought a hunk of
wood
from the gallows where the Lincoln
conspirators were hung.
And it includes a scan of the um of a of
a handwritten letter dated 1889
>> um from the soldier who was one of the
members of the crew that took the
gallows down and he kept one of the
planks and then divided it up to give to
friends.
>> What was with that? Like you know
there's all these when they used to hang
people the the gallows often seemed to
be improvised. They didn't have a
permanent facility.
>> That's right.
>> Any Do you have any understanding of why
that is? I don't.
>> Well, be in this case, it's because um
people weren't normally hanged at at
this uh this base. It's it's the base
still exists. It's now Bowling Air Force
Base.
>> Um or or they call it joint base bowling
something something or other. They just
changed all the names a couple of years
ago. Uh now the site of the gallows is
the officer's tennis courts.
So there's no there's no trace that
these gallows were there and that they
hung the Lincoln conspirators
including the first woman to be executed
by the US government. So
>> wait, there was a woman there was a
woman conspirator.
>> Yeah, Mary Sarat
West House.
>> Um she she plotted with them and she's
the one that hid the the um gun that
John Wils Booth used. She hid it behind
the stove in her kitchen.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> So, yeah. I mean, I do I do I definitely
have a wish list for my political
ephemera collection. I I
>> All I'm lacking now is
>> I I want uh I want a pardon signed by
Abraham Lincoln. They're out there. They
go for about 10 to$14,000. I'm not in a
position to buy something like that, but
I'm hoping that 2026 turns out to be a
really great year for me. In which case,
I'm going to I'm going to grab one.
>> That's That's cool. I'd rather, frankly,
I'd rather you got a pardon signed by
President Trump, but that's just me.
>> Me, too.
>> Um, [laughter] so although the Lincoln
one sounds cool, too. Um, all right. So,
let's we should probably uh talk about u
the situation in Israel. All right. So,
let's talk with let's first like get
into the UN Security Council. So, we all
know I'm not we're not going to we
talked here on the show about the
20point plan and if you're watching this
show, you probably have a pretty good
idea of what's in here. Um but you know,
as I mentioned, John, it this is not a
plan that seems to have um you know,
enough enough meat on the bones to make
a lot of sense. Okay. So, there's a
peacekeeping force that I understand. Um
it it's going to be uh it's it's going
to be a bunch of Muslim countries like
including Pakistan. That I understand
too. But who are they keeping the peace
from? They're going to disarm Hamas. How
how are they Hamas says they don't want
to be disarmed. They they had no seat at
the table here. Um you know they called
this a international guardianship
mechanism which is kind of reminiscent
of like say the French mandate over
Lebanon and and that kind of thing. Um,
I don't think they're wrong. Um,
>> and then, uh, you know, basically this
is a non-ontiguous state.
Israel, by the way, just parathetically
rolling this back, you know, Hamas
justified October 7th by saying if they
hadn't done something like this, they
would have never achieved statehood.
Now,
Netanyahu says we will never agree to
the creation of a Palestinian state.
retroactively basically confirming what
Hamas said.
>> Um and and kind of justifying October
7th after the fact. Um I I guess
>> um it's like so many so easy to see all
the ways this passes through that this
can't work and yet this this agreement
now has the uh the force of
international law.
>> Yes, it does.
>> Is it a dead letter or or or is this are
they going to try to do this? [snorts]
Let let's try to parse it out. Um there
is no meat on the bone when it comes to
the issue of Palestinian statehood. So
the vote was 13 to nothing. Uh China and
Russia abstained just like we predicted
that they would do. And u
>> and nobody and the and the reporting
doesn't talk about China's abstension.
Only Russia's abstension.
>> Only Russia's. That's right. Um
but almost all of the council members,
France, Guyana, Pakistan, Slovenia,
Somalia, um complained that there was no
language about an independent
Palestinian state.
And that's where we're going to get
wrapped around the axle again. Um
everybody agrees that there needs to be
peace, there needs to be respect for
Palestinian human rights, etc., etc.
But Benjamin Netanyahu said, here's his
quote. I have it right here from the New
York Times. Our opposition to a
Palestinian state in any territory has
not changed. There will be no
independent Palestinian state if it's up
to the Israelis ever in any
configuration. It's not going to happen.
And so,
>> can it be forced? Can it be forced down
their throats is the question.
>> Or will it be? It can be, but will it?
can be
[snorts] not not as things sit today.
Now,
>> can the Israelis just be sidelined at a
certain point? Because I mean, you know,
international relationships re rely on
cooperation. If the Israelis are
uncooperative, maybe you just don't work
with them.
>> So, and and what do you think of this,
Ted?
Is this just an accident or is Donald
Trump a genius here where you've got we
you've got all these Arab countries um
Egypt, the United Arab Emirates,
Tunisia,
and other Muslim countries, Indonesia,
Turkey, that have agreed to send troops,
these peacekeeping troops, but they're
very afraid of their troops getting into
an armed conflict with Hamas. So, you're
going to have Muslim
armies
shooting
Hamas um
paramililitary forces, Arabs killing
Arabs, Muslims killing Muslims. Does Is
that what Donald Trump planned or did it
just kind of work out that way?
>> I don't think that's what he wants,
right? I I think I mean I think he's
really kind of hoping the Hamas will not
fire at them because they're Muslims and
that [clears throat] they'll be I mean
look I [laughter]
I guess another question is do you think
Ham do you think Hamas will handle this
the way the Afghans handle an invasion?
you know, they they go to ground. The
Afghans go to the mountains. Um they
they they study the enemy, then they do
probing attacks, and eventually they
come back and and and flood the field
and and the invaders never knew what hit
them. Obviously, there's no mountains in
Gaza to hide in, and they can't even
hide in those tunnels forever. But
basically, they can take off their
uniforms and slip back into uh into
civilian life and just wait to get the
call from their commanders, right? It's
a cell structure, right? like you know
you're my commanding officer and you
command me and like a couple other
people and then I have someone under me
and so on. Um
>> is I mean it's a resistance
organization. It's a classic resistance
organization.
>> Classic. Um so will they just sort of
okay guys you know just go back home try
to rebuild the best you can and uh you
know we'll outlast and outweight these
Pakistanis and so on and then uh you
know we'll we'll get our country back. I
mean what do you what do you what do you
is it going to look like that? [snorts]
>> I think it very well could. Um the the
bottom line though is is what we said a
minute ago. The Israelis are going to
have to be forced into this. And it
really, we do need to force the Israelis
into this. There has to be an
independent Palestine. There must
>> be. There has to be. There has to be.
>> There's no other alternative. There has
to be
>> for for Israel's own good, by the way.
>> And what and an independent Palestine
was called for in the Security Council
resolution that created the state of
Israel in the first place.
>> And and reasonable Israelis all know
this is essential for their own
security. Yes. Um, exactly right.
>> And by the way, the the non nobody is
addressing the contin the uh the contigu
what's the the noun for contiguous
>> contiguity.
>> Contigu contiguity.
[laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> Anyway, the fact that it's not
contiguous, the fact that it's not
[__] attached,
>> that's a problem. I mean to ask ask
Pakistan whether that's a problem or
not.
>> Yeah, that's right. That's right. Now
they made it work in Bosnia Herzgoina,
but that was an unusual situation,
>> right? I mean I mean look, so the
Israelis I don't see them giving
granting a corridor,
>> but but they but they have to, right?
>> They're going to have to
>> I mean I guess a bridge, right? Like a
big long bridge like the way that they
have over the Florida Keys
>> so that the Israelis can go underneath
and stuff.
>> Oh my god. I can't even imagine.
>> It's got to be some Well, it's not that
far, right? I think before that happens,
we're going to see the proposed uh Trump
Putin bridge tunnel connecting uh
Siberia with Alaska.
>> I I want By the way, I that's actually a
good idea.
>> Yeah, I would I would actually drive it
just to say I did.
>> I also think it's a really I do think
it's a good idea for political and
economic reasons. I mean, it's like I
mean,
>> Siberia, I I it would be great for
American business to have access to
Siberia.
>> And it would be fun. You know what I did
with my kids a couple of Christmases
ago? Christmas I I find Christmas to be
very very depressing. And I I don't
decorate. I don't put up any
>> any tree or decorations or anything. I
just pretend it's a normal day like
every other day just because I get too
depressed to even function. So,
>> how come you always were you like that
as a kid? Were you always like that?
>> No. No. Christmas was wonderful when I
was a kid, but I don't know. I'm
divorced twice and it's just not I I
just can't do it. So, what I did with
the kids a couple of years ago, I said,
"Hey,
>> let's open your presents and then let's
get on the subway and we'll go to every
single station on the entire subway
system without
>> You can do that in New York City."
>> Oh, you can do it in New York City.
There was an article about it in the
Times and a guy did it in 25 hours which
is like record fast.
>> I was going to say because I've been to
every station in the New York City
subway system and uh I used to explore
it in college and I was going to say
you'd have to it would take a long time.
>> A lot of planning because there's a lot
of backtracking. But anyway, we did it
in nine and a half hours
>> and we did take a break. We did actually
come up out of the station at the zoo
and we had lunch and then we went back
down in and finished it.
>> We have similar impulses. I'm I'm not a
big fan of the holidays either. I I hate
Thanksgiving more than Christmas. Um and
uh but I once spent Thanksgiving uh
sorry Christmas day with two friends
exploring the abandoned uh subway
tunnels under Cincinnati. I don't know
if you know about that,
>> but there was a fact my son and I were
just talking about it day before
yesterday. Cincinnati has more abandoned
subway tunnels than any other city in
America.
>> It's a it's it's I I don't know if it's
a I I bet it's not as accessible as it
used to be, but back in the day you
could just like there was a place in
near in a public park where you just
break where someone had broken in and
you could just like walk in there if you
just brought
>> bring a flashlight and plenty of
batteries and you could
>> walk like 12 miles. It was really crazy.
And there's fallout shelters in there
from from the from the Cold War. Wow.
Including with like a podium where
someone where you know someone they
people were going to address the crowds.
There's a locked arsenal that you
couldn't break into.
>> I mean it there were bet there was
bedding uh you know it was it was really
cool. And in the end finally you you
you're sort of like there's a ladder.
It's like oh I think this is the way
out. Climb the ladder and there's a
manhole cover and you you lift the
manhole and there's cars going over.
And it's like, oh, oh, better better
time this carefully. Um,
yeah. Yeah, it was it was cool. Anyway,
um, so, okay, so this so so I do think
that Trump, to get back to your main
question, though, he is kind of a genius
in that as [__] up as this plan is,
>> this is progress, right? I mean, I don't
think we'd be here with under President
Biden or President Harris. Um, yeah, I
think I think the Israelis would still
be bombing.
>> I agree with you. As pro- Israel and
pro-Zionist as Donald Trump is,
he expects people to do as they're told.
>> And Netanyahu won't do as he's told. And
so, you've got to force him.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's the thing about is
Trump. He does understand
power and leverage. It's the only thing
he really understands, but he
understands them really well. And you
know, I I still have to say I'm in
complete agreement with Tucker Carlson
and his rant about, you know, Israel is
inconsequential. We don't need them.
They're a liability. We should have
nothing to do with them. And we don't
need to be We have lots of friends in
the Middle East. You know, we get along
with We have Jordan. We have Egypt. We
don't need Israel. Um this tiny little
country with no natural resources at
all. I mean,
>> that's right.
>> It's it's Egypt's far more important. Um
anyway, that's just so okay, let's talk
about this South Africa story. I'm
fascinated by this. Yeah.
>> So, so this is
>> Nobody knew this was happening.
>> This is a dark story. So, so basically
these Palestinians are reporting, well,
this happened, right? So, basically
these Gazins were told, "Hey, so like I
know how you can get out. If you want to
get out, you got to give me $1600 in
crypto per person in your family who
wants to leave." and then show up at a
certain point and we've got it all
figured out. So for the people who
decided to to bite on this, which
probably wasn't most of them because
there's so many scammers, so many lying
sacks of [__] in a war zone situation
like that that you know, you'd be very I
mean you that's a leap a serious leap of
faith that most people wouldn't take.
But some people did. And for those
people, they ended up being put on a bus
and routed down to Kunis and then um and
then taken to the border crossing uh and
waved by by Israeli troops. And the
Israeli troops uh finally right before
they left the Gaza the the occupied
territory of Gaza. This is this is very
sinister. The Israelis said, "You have
to leave all of your belongings behind."
And then so they so just with the
>> just Yeah. very familiar. Um very 1942.
And they they they they got they were
they boarded uh they they got into
Israel proper. They were taken to the
airport and uh and then flown. They they
didn't know where they were going. Um
this one group they flew to Kenya. They
went to Nairobi. Um and then they were
stuck for 10 hours on the airport
tarmac. They have no idea where they're
going. This is also familiar. It reminds
me of the ship um the St. Louis, right,
that uh during World War II that's you
know flying around. But maybe this was
all part of the plan.
>> Um this obscure charity that appears to
have serious probably be a front
organization for the Israeli government
or for the MSAD or both. um and then uh
basically arranged all this and they
found themselves in the Republic of
South Africa. South Africa has long
historic ties supporting the
Palestinians for obvious uh political
and uh cultural reasons. And um and so
the South Africans, this has been going
on for a while. And now the foreign the
foreign minister uh Ronald Lamola
finally became aware of it and he's
like, "Wait, wait, wait. We see what
you're doing here. You're you're like we
we welcome our Palestinian friends and
brothers, but you're ethnically
cleansing the Gaza Strip." Like drip by
drip by drip. And there's been a lot of
flights to other countries in Africa and
possibly other continents as well. Um
this this is what it looks like, right?
It does. It I mean the South Africans
are right
>> and this is this is exactly what the
Egyptians have been have been um warning
against since since this whole thing
started is yes, they love their
Palestinian brothers. Yes, they want to
help. But to open the border and allow
Palestinians to come across the border
into Sinai would do nothing but to abet
um Israel's policy of ethnic cleansing.
That's it. Yeah. You can't do it.
>> No. Because as soon as that happens, the
Israelis are like, "Well, what can you
do? It's empty now." It's like, "You
gonna eat that or what? If you won't, we
will." And then they move in. And and
it's a fat. I mean, that's already what
they've done to 60% of the West Bank.
>> Yes. Exactly.
>> Exactly.
>> It's so I mean, I got to say I admire
the level of cynicism. It's amazing.
>> It is. And you know, one of the things
that's pleasantly surprising to me, and
don't take this the wrong way, because I
I don't mean that, you know,
Palestinians should suffer more than
they have already, but it's it's good
and it's important for these countries
to stand up to the Israelis. Finally,
stand up to them and say no.
>> Yeah, for sure. Um, thanks for the
donations over on YouTube, guys. Much
appreciate the super chats. Um $4.99
from Marorrow. Uh really really
appreciate that. Um and uh thanks thanks
for tuning in. Alex Bruce also $499.
Thank you very much. Uh he's a Christian
who leans conservative but greatly
appreciates our insights. Thank you very
much. I hope we're not blurry on my on
my YouTube. We're blurry but I don't
know.
>> Mine looks pretty good.
>> Okay. So that's probably that packet
issue that that Robbie filled me in
filled us in about yesterday. So
um yeah, so I guess that puts an end to
it. I mean, what happens to these people
when they get to South Africa with not
with just the clothes on their back? I
mean, one of the
>> one of the girls from little girls from
the family said she loved being able to
go to the store and buy things uh
something they couldn't do in Gaza. Um
>> obviously someone's giving the money so
that that can happen. So there must be a
support infrastructure there.
>> I I really fear that they're going to be
forcibly returned.
>> Do you think I really I'm
>> I can't imagine that.
>> I hope I I seriously I can't imagine the
South Africans doing that. I mean
they've been such a good friend to the
Palestinian people at like the ICJ and
everything. I mean I just don't see it.
Well um yeah. Um, I'm trying to look see
if there's any last second questions or
comments um that we need to get to
before we say until tomorrow. Um, okay,
good. We don't look blurry. Okay, quick,
very quickly, uh, John, off-topic
question. Have you been follow following
Kuwaiti news at all? If so, any
thoughts?
>> I have been following Kuwaiti news, as a
matter of fact. Um there is a very
serious significant split in the Kuwaiti
royal family that has spilled into the
media [snorts] and um
I'm worried about it because the the
Kuwaiti response has been to dissolve
parliament which isn't going to help the
split in their family any. We'll see
where it goes.
>> Okay. Well, uh I I have no I was not
asked that question and I'm glad because
I don't have an answer for that
question. Guys, thank you so much for
tuning in to the program with Ted
Rollins, John Kuryaku. Uh we will be
back tomorrow, Wednesday, five, h sorry,
900 am Eastern time. We're here Monday
through Friday. Please like, follow, and
share the show. Please stay tuned to the
TMI show with me, Ted R, and Manila Chan
coming up right after this. And uh take
care and see you tomorrow, John. Take
care and uh talk.
>> Bye bye, Ted. Bye.
>> Take care.
>> [music]